RG 004:138, Stratford Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Stratford Probate Court records
1781-1898
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Stratford District)
20.75 cubic feet
Record books, 1782-1840; Probate files, 1781-1898.
RG004_138
1916-006, 2011-006
Historical Note
Stratford, Fairfield County, Town settled in 1639
Stratford Probate District was constituted May 1782, from the Fairfield Probate District. It also served the following municipalities at various times: Bridgeport, May 1821 - June 3, 1840; Monroe, May 1823 - June 1840; Shelton, January 1789 - June 1840; Trumbull, October 1797 - June 1840. The records of the Stratford District from May 1782 to June 4, 1840, are found in the Bridgeport Probate District. The Stratford Probate District serves the municipality of Stratford.
Town of Stratford, Probate District chronology:
1639 - 1665, New Haven Colony Jurisdiction
1639 - May 1666, Hartford Particular Court Jurisdiction
1649 - May 1666, Fairfield Particular Court Jurisdiction
May 1666 - May 1782, Fairfield County Court & District
May 1782 - Present, Stratford District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, volumes 1-10, 1782-1840. There is a separate index volume. Contact the probate court to access original record books after volume 10. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1781-1898. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1781-1898 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books in accessions 2011-006 are numnbered 1 to 10. There are two volumes each for numbers 6, 7, 8, and 9, with one volume being for Records and the other for Journal. The index volume in unnumbered.
Probate files in accession 1916-006 are arranged alphabetically.
Other Finding Aid
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1916-006 are represented in this index.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Bridgeport; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Monroe; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Shelton; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Stratford; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Trumbull
Places:
Bridgeport (Conn.); Monroe (Conn.); Shelton (Conn.); Stratford (Conn.); Trumbull (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accession 2011-006, Record books, 1782-1840, is stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
Probate files dated 1921 or later are RESTRICTED pending review by State Archives staff as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Removals of parent as guardian of minor (all documents) and terminations of parental rights (all documents) from October 1, 1975 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1-12, 1782-1851; volumes 1-5, 9, 10, 13, 14, 17, 18, 20, 21, 1840-1917; probate files, 1766-1880 (Accession 1916-006); and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1916-006 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): May 22, 1916 (1781-1898); June 17, 1932 (1782-1859); March 29, 1933 (1782-1859). They were interfiled into one alphbetic sequence.
The record books in accession 2011-006 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on July 26, 2010.
Container List
- Record books, 1782-1840; 7.5 cubic feet (14 volumes); 2011-006
  - Records and journal, 1782-1788 (Volume 1)
  - Records and journal, 1788-1795 (Volume 2)
  - Records and journal, 1795-1801 (Volume 3)
  - Records and journal, 1801-1805 (Volume 4)
  - Records and journal, 1805-1813; photostat (Volume 5)
  - Records, 1813-1820 (Volume 6)
  - Journal, 1811-1826; photostat (Volume 6)
  - Records, 1820-1829 (Volume 7)
  - Journal, 1826-1831; photostat (Volume 7)
  - Records, 1829-1834; photostat (Volume 8)
  - Journal, 1831-1836; photostat (Volume 8)
  - Records, 1834-1836; photostat (Volume 9)
  - Journal, 1836-1840; photostat (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1836-1840 (Volume 10)
  - Index, 1782-1840 (Volume unnumbered)
    This index also covers the Easton-Weston Probate District, volumes 1-4, 1832-1878
- Probate files, 1781-1898; 13.25 cubic feet; 1916-006
  - Adams - Beach, D. (Drawer 1)
  - Beach E. - Beardsley, C. (Drawer 2)
  - Beardsley, D. - Beardsley, R. (Drawer 3)
  - Beardsley, S. - Bennett (Drawer 4)
  - Betts - Blackman (Drawer 5)
  - Blagge - Brinsmade, D. (Drawer 6)
  - Brinsmade, E. - Burr (Drawer 7)
  - Burritt - Burton (Drawer 8)
  - Butler - Crofoot (Drawer 9)
  - Crosby - Curtis, Henry (Drawer 10)
  - Curtis, Hepsey - Curtis, S. (Drawer 11)
  - Curtis, T. - Edwards, A. (Drawer 12)
  - Edwards, B. - Fairchild, D. (Drawer 13)
  - Fairchild, E. - French, M. (Drawer 14)
  - French, N. - Hale (Drawer 15)
  - Hall - Hawley, Emmeline (Drawer 16)
  - Hawley, Ephraim - Hayt, G. (Drawer 17)
  - Hayt, H. - Hubbell, H. (Drawer 18)
  - Hubbell, I. - Hurd, Ebenezer (Drawer 19)
  - Hurd, Electa - Judson, C. (Drawer 20)
  - Judson, D. - Lake (Drawer 21)
  - Lamson - Lewis, G. (Drawer 22)
  - Lewis, H. - MacEwen, D. (Drawer 23)
  - MacEwen, E. - Mansfield (Drawer 24)
  - Marks - Nails (Drawer 25)
  - Newton - Nichols (Drawer 26)
  - Northrop - Peck, J. (Drawer 27)
  - Peck, K. - Plumb, H. (Drawer 28)
  - Plumb, I. - Seeley, M. (Drawer 29)
  - Seeley, N. - Shelton, K. (Drawer 30)
  - Shelton, L. - Sherman (Drawer 31)
  - Sherwood - Staples (Drawer 32)
  - Sterling - Summers, R. (Drawer 33)
  - Summers, S. - Tomlinson, D. (Drawer 34)
  - Tomlinson, E. - Ufford, D. (Drawer 35)
  - Ufford, E. - Walker, J. (Drawer 36)
  - Walker, K. - Wells (Drawer 37)
  - West - Wheeler, John (Drawer 38)
  - Wheeler, Joseph - Wilcoxson (Drawer 39)
  - Williams - Z.; Miscellaneous (Drawer 40)
- Inventory Control Book, 1781-1898; T003073
  Index of the three accessions of probate files merged into accession 1916-006
  Also known as the Godard Digest